Guide to the Samuel Steward Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Samuel Steward papers
1930-2003
GEN MSS 987
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
20.46
(32 boxes)
Correspondence, writings, diaries, photographs, artwork, research materials, printed materials, and other papers by, to, or related to Samuel Steward. Correspondents include Gertrude Stein, Alice B. Toklas, George Platt Lynes, and Thornton Wilder. Writings include drafts of homoerotic novels written under the nom de plume Phil Andros, and a translation of Querelle of Brest by Jean Genet. A focus of the papers is Steward's sexual exploits, which are documented in diaries, photographs, and other papers, including Steward's stud file cataloging his sexual partners and records and writings produced for sexologist Alfred Kinsey. The papers also include writings, photographs, clippings, artwork, and other materials related to Steward's work as a tattoo artist, including correspondence from Don Ed Hardy. Artwork includes pen and ink tracings of illustrations by Jean Cocteau, for Genet's Querelle, a portrait of Gertrude Stein by Carl Van Vechten inscribed by Stein, and a charcoal portrait of Alice B. Toklas.
Steward, Samuel M., 1909-1993
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Justin Spring and Michael Williams on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2012.
August 2012 Acquisition: purchased from Elysium Press on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2012.
October 2012 Acquisition: gift of Michael Williams, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Samuel Steward (1909-1993)
Samuel Steward was an American writer and university professor who left the world of academia to become a tattoo artist and pornographer. Steward kept extensive records of his sex life, including diaries, journals, and a stud list. He lived and worked in Chicago, Illinois, and later Oakland, California.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, writings, diaries, photographs, artwork, research materials, printed materials, and other papers by, to, or related to Samuel Steward. Correspondents include Gertrude Stein, Alice B. Toklas, George Platt Lynes, and Thornton Wilder. Writings include drafts of homoerotic novels written under the nom de plume Phil Andros, and a translation of Querelle of Brest by Jean Genet. A focus of the papers is Steward's sexual exploits, which are documented in diaries, photographs, and other papers, including Steward's stud file cataloging his sexual partners and records and writings produced for sexologist Alfred Kinsey. The papers also include writings, photographs, clippings, artwork, and other materials related to Steward's work as a tattoo artist, including correspondence from Don Ed Hardy. Artwork includes pen and ink tracings of illustrations by Jean Cocteau, for Genet's Querelle, a portrait of Gertrude Stein by Carl Van Vechten inscribed by Stein, and a charcoal portrait of Alice B. Toklas.
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: June 2012 Acquisition, August 2012 Acquisition, and October 2012 Acquisition.
Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Novelists, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Gay authors -- United States -- Archives; Pornography -- United States -- History -- 20th Century; Sexology -- Research -- United States -- History -- 20th Century; Tattoo artists -- New York (State) -- New York -- Biography; Diaries -- United States -- 20th Century; Drawings (visual works); Photographs; Video recordings; LGBTQ resource; Cocteau, Jean, 1889-1963; Hardy, Don Ed, 1945-; Genet, Jean, 1910-1986; Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles), 1894-1956; Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946; Steward, Samuel M., 1909-1993; Toklas, Alice B, 1877-1967; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975
- June 2012 Acquisition, 1930-2003; 20.17; (30 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged roughly in the order in which it was received.
  - Chicago - assorted photocopies and newspaper clippings (Box 1)
  - Chicago Burglary 1965 - 3 pages, photocopies, newspaper clipping on tattoos (Box 1)
  - Renslow, Charles "Chuck," - 1 typed letter signed regarding Kinsey Institute / 1 autographed letter signed, photographs, clippings regarding tattoos (Box 1)
  - Leather Archives & Museum (LAM) materials - photocopies (Box 1)
  - Fritscher, Jack - photocopies (Box 1)
  - Leather Archives & Museum (LAM) - notes including Raven, Renslow interviews, photocopies (Box 1)
  - Steward interview, Len Evans - photocopies, 2 (Box 1)
  - Steward interview, video, Olaf Odergaard, Barney / Carpenter Library (Los Angeles, CA) - photocopies (Box 1)
  - Steward interview, Maves - photocopies (Box 1)
  - Steward interview, Sprague - photocopies (Box 1)
  - Steward interview, Rofes - photocopies (Box 1)
  - Steward obituaries - photocopies (Box 1)
  - Steward college transcript from Ohio State University - photocopies, 1930s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Steward author questionnaire, vita - photocopies, 1980s (Box 1)
  - Steward bibliography - photocopies, 2 (Box 1)
  - Raven, Cliff (Cliff Ingram), interview by Jack Rinella, LAM - photocopies, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Steward, Gay Sunshine interview, Winston Leyland interviewer - original transcription by Steward, with edits by Steward, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Steward, Contemporary Authors - photocopies (Box 1)
  - Steward - dissertation abstract, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Steward, dissertation - original typescript, 243 pages (Box 1)
  - Steward, miscellaneous notes - 15 pages, typescript with edits, 3 pages, manuscripts, miscellaneous autographed letters signed from unknown hand (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Steward books - photocopies, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Steward, reviews of pornography - photocopies, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Raven, Cliff (Cliff Ingram) - photocopies (Box 1)
  - Kinsey, Alfred - photocopies, 1 card from Wardell and Martha Pomeroy, clippings (Box 1)
  - "About Sexual Record-Keeping" - photocopies (Box 1)
  - Burke Affair / San Francisco Sentinel - photocopies, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Wilcox, Wendell including Gertrude Stein material - 12 pages, autographed letters signed and typed letters signed., circa 1981 (Box 1)
  - Oakland Police (and Oakland crime) - 1 Steward autographed letter signed and typed letter signed, circa 1981 (Box 1)
  - Steward, Oakland Years / Oakland crime - photocopy, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Police officers - typed letter, photocopy, Steward, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Porn publishers - 20 typed letters signed from various publishers, Advocate etc., regarding porn and publications, 1980s (Box 1)
  - Saylor, Steven (aka Aaron Travis), Drummer Magazine - assorted typed letters signed and photocopies, 1980s (Box 1)
  - J. Brian, L including material from SIR and VECTOR Magazine, newspaper clppings, assorted correspondence, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Autographed letter signed from Funnell ["Foot Fetishist / Dom Orejudas"] - 5 pages, photocopies, 1980s (Box 1)
  - Williams, Tennessee and Rome - photocopies, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Wecott, Glenway - photocopies (Box 1)
  - Zabel, Morton Dawen - Steward typed letter signed, photocopy (Box 1)
  - Der Kreis - assorted letterhead from Der Kreis, letters from DK from '60s, 1 typed letter, photocopy from Steward, 1960s (Box 1)
  - Book Auctions featuring Steward letters and books, various appraisals and inventory lists of books, detailed Steward book consignments., 2003 (Box 1)
  - John Preston - approximately 27 autographed letters signed, typed letters signed, postcards regarding assorted matters, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Article on Phil Sparrow in Chicago magazine, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Journal articles on Sam Steward photocopies (Box 1)
  - (Good) magazine articles on Steward (Box 1)
  - Bronski, Michael on Steward and S/M - photocopy (Box 1)
  - Tattoo Book photocopy (Box 1)
  - Articles on Tattooing - photocopy, assorted ephemera (including business cards), 1980s; 2 (Box 1)
  - Nonfiction articles by Steward - 47 pages, photocopies and typescripts of essays, some with editorial notes (Box 1)
  - "A Visit with Thomas Mann" by Steward - photocopy articles (Box 1)
  - Eos / amigo articles by Steward - 5 typed letters signed from Eos and 1 page essay on tattooing with corrections by Steward (Box 1)
  - Assorted Steward short fiction - 63 pages, typescripts with corrections by hand, clippings (Box 1)
  - Waugh, Thomas, selections from "Hard to Imagine" - photocopy (Box 1)
  - Tattoo Journal by Steward, original pages from, miscellaneous photocopies (Box 1)
  - On George Platt Lynes, including original letter by Jack Woody regarding sale of Steward Lynes photographs - 3 pages, autographed letters signed from Woody to Steward, 10 pages, corrected manuscript on George Platt Lynes by Steward, 1980s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Angels on the Bough - photocopy (Box 1)
  - Tom of Finland - 3 typed letters signed and inscribed photos of artwork, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Steward Memorial Service photographs with notes by Michael William, quantity of photos, 2 (Box 1)
  - Steward birth certificate - photocopies (Box 1)
  - Steward, purchase of 2016-x Ninth Street Berkeley, quantity of photocopies and autographed letters signed, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Morihien, Paul - 1 typed letter signed and draft from Steward, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Greenleaf Classics - 4 typed letters signed regarding publications, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Olympia Press correspondences, 2 typed letters signed, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Fairbanks, Harold - 1 typed letter signed and ephemera, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Gebhard, Paul - 4 typed letters signed with carbon response, circa 1973 (Box 2)
  - Toklas, Alice B., two original notes to Steward left at the Hotel Recamier (Box 2)
  - Ellis, Havelock, 1 autographed letter signed, 2 pages with envelope, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Steward, incoming letters of minimal importance, a quantity, 1980s-1990s; 3 (Box 2)
  - Steward, outgoing letters of minimal importance - 12 typed letters, photocopy, 1960s-1970s (Box 2)
  - Rumaker, Michael - 1 typed letter signed, 1 autographed letter signed, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Crisp, Quentin - 1 autographed letter signed, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Mesrobian, Michael - 1 autographed letter signed, 1 autographed letter signed card, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Hadleigh, Boze - 1 typed letter signed, 2 typed letters signed, cards, 1991 (Box 2)
  - White, Douglas - 2 typed letters signed, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Leyland, Winston - 1 typed letter signed, 1 autographed letter signed card (Box 2)
  - Steward, interesting letters to various - 1 typed letter signed from Kiernan Preather, Steward's response, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Gildzen, A - 2 typed letters signed, quantity of printed cards regarding publication of postcard book, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Rofes, Eric - 1 autographed letter signed, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Young, Gordon - 2 pages typed letter signed, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Woodsfield, Ohio, original photos, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Picano, Felice - 1 pages typed letter signed, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Whitmore, George - Newspaper clipping, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Kantrowitz, Arnie - 1 autographed letter signed, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Barney, Jeanne - 1 autographed letter signed, 3 cards, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Martin John (Dance critic for the New York Times) - 5 typed letters signed, 1 autographed letter signed cards, 1955-1958 (Box 2)
  - Fairbanks, Harold - 2 cards, 1989-1993 (Box 2)
  - Pomeroy, Wardell - 2 typed letters signed, 3 cards, 1965-1990s (Box 2)
  - Padgette, Paul - 7 cards, 1 typed letter signed, 1977-1991 (Box 2)
  - McCarty, VK (aka Mam'selle Victoire from Pentouse Magazine) - 2 cards, assorted photocopies, 1990s (Box 2)
  - Califia, Pat - 1 typed letter signed, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Steward, health problems, medical correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 2)
  - Steward, seach for AIDS cure - 2 typed letters signed regarding research, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Kain, Art (empty envelope), 1942 (Box 2)
  - Walker, G and Molda, Eddie - 1 typed letter signed, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Von Phitzer, Juniper - 1 typed letter signed, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Caen, Herb - 1 typed letter signed, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Gallup, Donald - 1 typed letter signed, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Mariah, Paul - 1 card, 1 letter, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Bazin, Rene (autograph) inscription on 1/3 title page (Box 2)
  - Steward, family letters - 5 autographed letters signed, 1941-1942 (Box 2)
  - Sterret, Sherman (from Helena, MT) - 3 cards, 1981-1992 (Box 2)
  - Frost, Ernest - 2 typed letters signed, 5 cards, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Miles, Alan - 1 typed letter signed, 2 cards, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Howard, Adam - 6 cards, 1 autographed letter signed, 1991-1993 (Box 2)
  - Austen, Roger - 1 cards, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Tellman, Bill - 3 cards, 1989-1993 (Box 2)
  - Pardi, Don - 3 cards, 1989-1993 (Box 2)
  - Hardy, Don "Ed" (tattooist) - 4 cards, 1989-1992 (Box 2)
  - Wright, Steven (anthology editor of "Different," 1975) - 1 typed letter signed (Box 2)
  - Earliest Phil Andros reviews (see also Fairbanks, Austen and Wright), 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Steward book parties and readings (announcements) - Quantity of ephemeral material, 2 (Box 2)
  - Steward, verse by, circa 1980 (Box 2)
  - Ferguson, Richard - 2 typed letters signed, 1987-1993 (Box 2)
  - Field, Marshall - 1 typed letter signed, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Mysterious fragments, unknown origin, circa 1980s (Box 2)
  - Steward, queries by - photocopies, 1936-1970s (Box 2)
  - Steward, 1950s fiction by - 17 pages T corrected "Revelation" (Box 2)
  - Steward, early erotica by - 6 pages incomplete corrected typescript (Box 2)
  - Steward, Womack/Potomac STUD contract, original and copies, circa 1965 (Box 2)
  - Steward, journal articles, academic (Box 2)
  - Steward, DePaul interview, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Steward, Royalty stubs, 1979-1985 (Box 2)
  - Steward, Virginia (aka Virginia "Ginny" or "Jinny" Ury) - Letters to Steward, 1930s-1990s (Box 2)
  - Steward, introduction to Quatrefoil by James Barr (Fugate) - 4 pages typed corrected manuscript, circa 1981 (Box 2)
  - Steward, regarding Hustling Book - photocopies (Box 2)
  - Steward, early short autobiographical fiction - 11 pages typescript corrected, "The Rich Man's Door", circa 1940s (Box 2)
  - Steward, Dachshunds of, including memorial (Box 2)
  - Weiss, Burton - 5 autographed letters signed and typed letters signed regarding purchase of artworks, 1980s-1990s (Box 2)
  - Andrews, Clarence - 2 pages autographed letter signed, 1930-1986 (Box 2)
  - Steward, Death - Assorted publications (Box 2)
  - Steward, mailing lists, assorted holograph lists and typed (Box 2)
  - Steward, play about Stein, Bilignin - 21 pages typescript with holograph corrections (Box 2)
  - Steward, donations to charity includign Kemper Archive - photocopies, 1960s-1990s (Box 2)
  - Steward, financial - photocopy, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Toklas, Alice, Musicale Programme - photocopy (Box 2)
  - Delarue, Jacques, tattoo photographs - 6 (Box 2)
  - Steward, photos of - A quantity, different formats (Box 2)
  - Steward, amusements and diversions for, assorted clippings, postcards, 1 holograph poem by Steward (Box 2)
  - Steward, notes for Shuttlecock (Andros) - 3 pages CC, preliminary sketch for book (Box 2)
  - Steward, original drafts of Phil Andros stories (Box 2)
  - Steward, typed and holograph notes on Tattoo Journal written for Kinsey - 5 pages (Box 2)
  - Steward, Shuttlecock (Andros), original draft of, typescript, holograph corrections (Box 2)
  - Steward, "Tattooing and Sex," original draft, 12 pages with corrections [page 1 missing] (Box 3)
  - Steward vg, "Pussies in Boots" (Box 3)
    Scope and Contents
    In mat.
  - Playguy magazine, vol. 5, no. 10, article on Hardin, Maceo ("Johnny") (Box 3)
  - Menendez, Johnny (including photos) (Box 3)
  - Lucky, Ervin - autographed letter signed and notes (Box 3)
  - Ballet Photographs, Autographed 6 (Box 3)
  - Kane, Jim (and partner/slave Barnes, Ike) - Cards and ephemera (Box 3)
  - Shults, Dan - 6 autographed letters signed and cards, book of poems (Box 3)
  - Andersen, Scott, cards, photographs, ephemera, 2 (Box 3)
  - Bullock, Roger, inscribed music score (Box 3)
  - Schuler, Ralph - 1 card (Box 3)
  - Costa, Pete - 5 typed letters signed and cards (Box 3)
  - Pick, Witold (Vitold) - small card (Box 3)
  - Steward, early draft of "Hustler" - holograph corrections (Box 3)
  - Steward, Articles of interest to and saved by (Box 3)
  - Steward, The Tattoo Jungle odds and ends - photocopies (Box 3)
  - Stein, Gertrude, assorted correspondence related to book (Box 3)
  - Burns, Edward - 1 holograph card (Box 3)
  - Steward, 1939 trip to France ship menu (Box 3)
  - Steward, outline for a Stein mystery - 28 pages with holograph notes (Box 3)
  - Steward, copies of letters from Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas (originals now in Beinecke and Bancroft collection) - photocopies and stationery samples (Box 3)
  - Nava, Michael - 3 autographed letters signed with typed response (Box 3)
  - Austen, Roger - signed card (Box 3)
  - White, Edmund - signed card (Box 3)
  - Hall, Richard - autographed letter signed regarding Wilder (Box 3)
  - Lynes, George Platt, letters to Steward - 10 autographed letters signed, 2 photo cards, 1 small photo, 1950s (Box 3)
  - Steward, letters to George Platt Lynes - photocopies (Box 3)
  - Field, Edward - 4 typed letters signed, assorted related material and book (Box 3)
  - Bean, Joseph - 2 pages typed letter signed from Steward (Box 3)
  - Kundrat - assorted cards (Box 3)
  - McCabe, Jerry - 6 typed letters signed (Box 3)
  - Rechy, John - 6 typed letters signed, 1 card, 1960s including letters to Rudy Burckhardt (Box 3)
  - White, Max - Letters to and from Steward, 3 typed letters signed and carbon replies (Box 3)
  - Anger, Kenneth - 1 typed letter signed and card regarding Scorpio rising (Box 3)
  - Purdy, James - 7 typed letters signed, 11 cards (Box 3)
  - Steward, Kern County Land Ownership - assorted documents, photocopies (Box 3)
  - Townsend, Larry - cc from Steward (Box 3)
  - Shuttlecock screenplay - typescript 24 pages (Box 3)
  - Steward daschunds - miscellaneous photocopy (Box 3)
  - Dental Journal articles saved by Ginny Steward (Box 3)
  - Steward, letters [to Virginia Steward Ury] (Box 3)
  - Steward, auction records (Box 3)
  - Steward, Emmy Curtis papers - photocopies (Box 3)
  - Steward, property deed for 2016-x Ninth Street, Berkeley (Box 3)
  - Steward, entries and articles on Steward in encyclopedias and Who's Who - photocopies (Box 3)
  - Steward, article on Political Correctness - 1 page (Box 3)
  - Steward, early poetry - 8 holograph poems, 1930s (Box 3)
  - Steward - Memoir of Kinsey filming - 15 pages typescript (Box 3)
  - Steward, assorted receipts (Box 3)
  - Rose, Francis - Clippings, 1 autographed letter signed, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Steward, assorted notes by (Box 3)
  - Steward, article about in DePaul newspaper (Box 3)
  - Isherwood, Christopher - 4 cards, 1 autographed letter signed (Box 3)
  - Steward, correspondence to and from biographer Linda Simon regarding Thornton Wilder's cards (Box 3)
  - Steward, Last Will and Testament and assorted testamentary papers (Box 3)
  - Assorted press clippings regarding Steward, 2 (Box 3)
  - Steward, Montana notebook - 100 pages holograph (Box 4)
  - Steward, Kern County Land Ownership (Box 4)
  - Williams, Michael, correspondence with friends of Steward at the time of his death, assorted letters and responses (Box 4)
  - Steward, regarding St. Procopius Church, miscellaneous documents (Box 4)
  - Steward, Harvey Clar's Estate Auctions, regarding sale of books (Box 4)
  - Steward, asset sales, bookkeeping (Box 4)
  - Woody, Jack and Twin Palms Publishers, book catalog (Box 4)
  - 5 ledgers, 3 (Box 4)
  - 3 Calendars, 1988-1990 (Box 4)
  - Santayana, George - 1 page, autographed letter signed 1948 vg. (Box 4)
  - Steward, World Book Encyclopedia job recommendation (Box 4)
  - Steward, Loyola Departure - 1 page typed letter signed, 1945-1946 (Box 4)
  - Steward on sex with black men - 1 page, typescript (Box 4)
  - Frisch/Womack re. STUD (Andros) 12 typed letters signed, with Steward carbons (Box 4)
  - Delarue, Jacques - 7 typed letters signed, 9 pages (Box 4)
  - Curtis, Emmy, deceased, estate appraisal (Box 4)
  - Killian, Kevin, including memoir of Steward - 5 pages (Box 4)
  - Steward, Commonplace Collection, Steward assorted notes (Box 4)
  - "Sammy's Tattoo Shop" in Frankfurt, correspondence plus photos from German tattooist - 24 pages TL, 3 photos (Box 4)
  - Steward's tattoing source material, clippings, articles (Box 4)
  - Tattoo news (tattoo parlor closings) with references to Steward newsletters, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Steward sex calendars, 1973, 1975-1976, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Steward address book, 2 x extensive, undated, 2 (Box 4)
  - Steward 1964 Food/Transport Diary, record of expenses (Box 4)
  - Steward, drafts of assorted fiction (Box 4)
  - White, Edmund on San Francisco - photocopy (Box 4)
  - Prager, Robert - photocopy (Box 4)
  - Fritscher, Jack - photocopies (Box 4)
  - Gay before Stonewall with entries on Donald Webster Corey, Kinsey - photocopy (Box 4)
  - Steward electronics - photocopy receipts (Box 4)
  - Steward poscards, blanks (Box 4)
  - Steward family photos - 6 (Box 4)
  - Steward, World War II play (draft) - 44 pages typescript, corrected (Box 4)
  - Steward on World Book and religion (Box 4)
  - Press statements about Andros (Box 4)
  - Steward, Embarcadero YMCA - 11 pages typescript (Box 4)
  - Steward, assorted address books (Box 4)
  - Steward, collected writings for Der Kreis, 2 (Box 4)
  - Barr (Fugate), James, letters - photocopies (Box 4)
  - Loyola and DePaul - photocopies (Box 4)
  - Steward, assorted items from 1940s, including public speaking, clippings, assorted letters (Box 5)
  - Important clippings regarding Sam Steward (Box 5)
  - Barr (Fugate), James clipping (Box 5)
  - Steward, Chapters from an Autobiography "short version" draft manuscript - photocopy (Box 5)
  - Steward, Different Strokes "second copy" draft manuscript - photocopy (Box 5)
  - Steward, Bad Boys/Tough Tattoos "final pages" - photocopy, 2 (Box 5)
  - Alyson, Sasha (and Allison Publications) correspondence - a quantity with copies, 2 (Box 5)
  - Houghton Mifflin, Dear Sammy (Box 5)
  - Albino Verlag (Box 5)
  - Decline letters to Steward (Box 5)
  - Postal seizures material (Box 5)
  - St. Martin's Press correspondence (Box 5)
  - Gray Fox Press correspondence (Box 5)
  - Haworth, John De Cecco et. al. publication correspondence (Box 5)
  - Main Street Press, Gay Book of Days (Box 5)
  - Steward, notes for Volume 2 of Autobiography - 2 pages original with notes (Box 5)
  - Steward, rough draft of Autobiography (very long) - A quantity typed with corrections and photocopies, ca. 200 pages, 3 (Box 5)
  - Steward, assorted outgoing letters to various people, 2 (Box 5)
  - Steward, assorted incoming letters from various people, 2 (Box 5)
  - Steward's "Gay Bestsellers" clipping (Box 5)
  - World Book Encyclopedia (children's book project) (Box 5)
  - Rowberry, John - card (Box 5)
  - Bachardy, Don, two notes plus photograph of Bachardy, drawing of Steward, 1976 November 9 (Box 5)
  - Washington State University at Pullman scandal, bulletin of AAUP (Box 5)
  - Steward's teaching notes on "The Modern Novel" - 12 assorted clippings, holograph cards, notes, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Steward, teaching notes and student papers (Box 5)
  - Steward, important sketchbook, 1950 (Box 5)
  - Steward, renouncing citizenship (Box 5)
  - Best Sam Steward photographs, including Steward photographs (Martin) (Box 6)
  - Steward family photographs (Box 6)
  - Steward, Philadelphia Gay News reviews (Box 6)
  - Declines of Steward Manuscripts (Box 6)
  - Steward, alcoholism (Box 6)
  - Steward, Illinois Dental Journal articles - Black binding (Box 6)
  - Steward dissertation - 243 pages (Box 6)
  - Typescript of unpublished novel about "Thomas Cave" - 8 x 11 binder (Box 6)
  - Steward 1953 translation of Querelle of Brest by Genet - 8 x 11 binder, loose, 2 (Box 6)
  - Steward, family scrapbooks - fragile, 3 (Box 6)
  - Box with "2 novels/1 college/1 soap opera" - Original typescripts, 288 pages and 268 pages, 1930s; 3 (Box 6)